

PROFILE

I am a DevOps Engineer with experience in implementing continuous integration and deployment (CI/CD) pipelines, monitoring and logging systems, and infrastructure automation. I have worked with various tools such as Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, and Kubernetes, as well as cloud platforms such as AWS and Azure. My expertise lies in designing and maintaining scalable, secure, and highly available environments.

CONTACT

LinkedIn:

https://za.linkedin.com/in/malcolm-fraser-98406361

EMAIL:

malcolmfrsr@gmail.com

SKILLS

- CI/CD pipelines: Jenkins, Buildkite
- Automation: Ansible, Cloudformation
- Containerization: Docker, Kubernetes
- Cloud Platforms: AWS, Azure (limited experience)
- Logging and Monitoring:
 Datadoa
- Programming Languages:
 Ruby, Bash, Python, C#

MALCOLM FRASER

DevOps Engineer

EDUCATION

Prestige Academy

January 2003 – December 2005 Web Development Diploma Award for "Best Web project"

Kylemore Secondary

January 1998 – December 2001 Matric (Final year of High School)

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

WORK EXPERIENCE

2U DevOps Engineer

January 2022-February 2024

- Implementing continuous integration and deployment (CI/CD) pipelines using Buildkite.
- Automating infrastructure using Ansible and Terraform.
- Managing Kubernetes clusters in AWS and on-premises.
- Creating and maintaining development and testing environments in AWS.

IMQS DevOps Engineer

October 2016-January 2022

- Maintained Jenkins pipelines and deployed software on both Windows and Linux servers.
- Used Ruby and Bash as primary programming languages.
- Deployed software in Docker containers on Linux servers.

Wyzetalk Software Developer

October 2014-October 2016

 Developed, maintained and supported the Wyzetalk Enterprise application.

- Databases: SQL, MongoDB
- Front-End Development: JavaScript, AngularJS, HTML
- Worked with database layers (SQL and Mongo) and backend services (NodeJS).
- Worked on front-end development using Javascript, AngularJS, and HTML.
- Wrote unit tests for software services.
- Used Python Script for background tasks.

Assima Junior Developer

February 2011–September 2014

- Designed, developed, and configured scalable services using SOA by using the IDesign method.
- Implemented software services according to UML designs.
- Wrote unit tests for software services.

Master Maths Flash Developer

February 2006–February 2011

- Developed learning material from storyboards for students.
- Developed and maintained Flash components.